KUMAR PRIYANSHU

 $+917004123035 \Leftrightarrow Bangalore, Karnataka$

kr.priyanshu0309@gmail.com \leftrightarrow linkedin.com/in/priyanshu0309 \leftrightarrow github.com/priyanshu5485

SUMMARY

Highly skilled Data Engineer with 2 years of experience in leading the design, implementation, and maintenance of complex software systems. Expert in DataBricks, PySpark, Python, and SQL with a strong background in relational data modeling and cloud systems. Proficient in workflow orchestration tools and notebook environments. Demonstrates excellent analytical, problem-solving, and communication skills.

KEY SKILLS

Programing and Scripting Python, C++, Java Big Data Technologies Hadoop, Spark, Kafka

Databases SQL, Hive

Data Pipeline Automation Experience with Jenkins.

Frameworks Python Web Frameworks, ReactJS
Cloud Platform Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Other Infrastructure Git as Version Control

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data EngineerAug 2022 - PresentLTIMindtreeBangalore, KA

- Led the design, development, and maintenance of complex data pipelines and architectures using DataBricks, PySpark, and SQL, enhancing performance and scalability.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define data requirements and deliver optimal data solutions.
- Utilized workflow orchestration tool Jenkins to streamline data processing tasks and managed version control and infrastructure deployment using Git.
- Implemented cloud-based solutions on AWS, optimizing resource efficiency and end-user experience.

MERN Intern

Mindtree

Feb 2022 - May 2022

Bangalore, KA

- Gained hands-on experience with the MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js) stack.
- Collaborated with senior developers to build and maintain web applications.
- Implemented responsive and dynamic user interfaces using React.js.

PROJECTS

Sybase Exit Project- Citi Bank. Improved efficiency in the ETL process, resulting in a 20% reduction in processing time. Utilized Big Data technologies, including Apache Hadoop, Spark, and Hive, to handle large volumes of financial data efficiently.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering, Sapthagiri College of Engineering Information Science and Engineering 2018 - 2022

CERTIFICATION

- Databricks Certified Associate Developer for Apache Spark 3.0.
- Python for beginners Learn all the basics of Python.